Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- United States Attorney for Western Pennsylvania, 1969-1975; VII.
  - News Releases, 2.
    - October-December, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Federal, state, local agents inspecting area clubs in Strike Force's "Operation Scofflaw", October 7, 1972; 6.
      - A federal crack down has severely dented the heroin market in the Western PA area, October 11, 1972; 7.
      - Eleven persons were indicted on charges growing out of an alleged Middle East-to-Pittsburgh heroin distribution ring, October 13, 1972; 8.
      - The special federal grand jury investigating traffic in narcotics and dangerous drugs in Western PA indicted 14 persons on charges of violating federal drug laws, October 16, 1972; 9.
      - A federal grand jury indicted two United Mine Workers officials for federal offenses associated with the death of Joseph Yablonski, October 17, 1972; 10.
      - A federal grand jury returned a 21 count indictment charging three members of the Westinghouse Archives Federal Credit Union with misapplication of funds, October 18, 1972; 11.
      - A five year sentence was imposed on Dr. Vincent Sundry for illegally distributing amphetamine capsules in violation of the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act, October 25, 1972; 12.
      - Eight Western PA police officers were indicted on charges of violating the U.S. civil rights laws, November 9, 1972; 13.
      - A federal court jury returned a guilty verdict against Delores Iannelli on charges under the Organized Crime Control Act of 1970, November 10, 1972; 14.
      - Federal authorities arrested Samuel Harris, the largest heroin supplier in the Greater Pittsburgh area, November 21, 1972; 15.
      - Judge Barron McCune sentenced Terrance Mandich to 25 years in a federal penitentiary for armed robbery, November 27, 1972; 16.
      - James Woods pleaded guilty to five counts of credit card fraud, November 29, 1972; 17.
      - Thornburgh will be among seven American citizens spending two weeks in Japan as guests of the Japanese government, December 2, 1972; 18.
    - January-March, 1973 (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - A federal grand jury indicted two Venango County brothers on six counts of receiving stolen motor vehicles, January 12, 1973; 1.
      - A federal court jury convicted Allegheny County Detective Bernard Joller of federal perjury charges, January 24, 1973; 2.
      - A federal court convicted Valerie Ullery on tax evasion charges, February 5, 1973; 3.
      - A federal district court judge dismissed Barry Quinones' claim seeking damages for an alleged failure by the Bureau of Narcotics and Dangerous Drugs (BNDD) to circulate information concerning his outstanding employment record, February 7, 1973; 4.
      - Samuel Ferraro, the former chief of Allegheny County District Attorney Robert Duggan's "Racket Squad" was indicted on charges of income tax fraud, February 13, 1973; 5.
      - Judge Barron McCune sentenced Edward P. Green to 60 days in jail and to pay a fine on charges of income tax evasion, February 13, 1973; 6.
      - A federal grand jury convicted eight area persons on charges of violating the anti-gambling provisions of the Organized Crime Control Act of 1970, February 14, 1973; 7.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Paul Hornick, Jr. on sixteen counts of violations of the Federal Firearms laws, February 15, 1973; 8.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Arthur Rocco on two counts of federal income tax fraud in connection with the Pittsburgh-to-Las Vegas gambling junket operation, February 15, 1973; 8.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Nathan Glassberg on four counts of tax fraud, February 15, 1973; 10.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Dr. Harry Lykens for willfully failing to file federal income tax returns, February 15, 1973; 11.
      - A federal court jury convicted Richard Mitchell of three sales of heroin and cocaine, February 15, 1973; 12.
      - Thornburgh addresses need for correctional reform at Youth and Government Conference sponsored by the Allegheny County League of Women Voters, February 17, 1973; 13.
      - The special federal grand jury investigating traffic in narcotics and dangerous drugs will convene to consider evidence of U.S. drug law violations, February 21, 1973; 14.
      - A federal grand jury indicted William Mellon Hitchcock on charges of tax fraud, February 21, 1973; 15.
      - The special federal grand jury investigating traffic in narcotics and dangerous drugs handed up indictments against 10 Pittsburgh area residents, February 22, 1973; 16.
      - William Mellon Hitchcock will be arraigned on charges of tax fraud, March 1, 1973; 17.
      - Thornburgh will address the annual banquet of the Westmoreland County Council American Legion honoring past county and district commanders, March 3, 1973; 18.
      - Samuel Harris pleaded guilty to three counts of federal income tax charges, March 6, 1973; 19.
      - Thornburgh will be among the criminal justice experts participating in "Colloquy '73" at Bucknell University, March 8, 1973; 20.
      - Samuel Ferraro will be arraigned tomorrow on charges of income tax fraud, March 8, 1973; 21.
      - A federal grand jury indicted accountant Emory Kohn on 22 counts of assisting in the preparation of false income tax returns, March 14, 1973; 22.
      - Herman and Nellie Huber were indicted today for income tax evasion, March 14, 1973; 23.
      - Agents of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) arrested three McKees Rocks men and seized firearms and ammunition in a raid, March 15, 1973; 24.
      - A federal court jury convicted Raymond Jackson and Roxanne Johnson of violations of the Federal narcotics laws, March 19, 1973; 25.
      - A federal grand jury charged Dr. David Higgins in a four count indictment with illegal drug sales and failure to maintain proper prescription records, March 20, 1973; 26.
      - Businessmen must recognize their own self-interest in the aggressive prosecution of white collar crime, March 21, 1973; 27.
      - Joseph Hutzler, a Pittsburgh police officer, pleaded no contest to charges of violating the Federal Civil Rights Act, March 23, 1973; 28.
      - The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit upheld the conviction of former McKeesport City Councilman Michael Newman of federal wiretapping charges, March 29, 1973; 29.
    - April-June, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Donald Crandall, the former police chief of North Versailles Township, was sentenced to a 30 day jail term on conspiracy and mail fraud charges, April 11, 1973; 1.
      - John Tauro was found guilty on six counts of causing the interstate transportation of stolen and forged securities, April 12, 1973; 2.
      - Judge William Knox sentenced Harry Heilman to three years imprisonment on charges of income tax evasion, April 13, 1973; 3.
      - Statement regarding court-authorized wire tapping, April 14, 1973; 4.
      - Dr. William Catena was found guilty on ten counts of submitting fraudulent Medicare claims, April 19, 1973; 5.
      - Frank Bruno will be arraigned on Tuesday before U.S. Magistrate Robert C. Mitchell, April 23, 1973; 6.
      - A force of nearly 60 FBI agents carried out coordinated raids on 21 suspected illegal gambling sites in Erie, PA., April 26, 1973; 7.
      - Judge Rabe Marsh sentenced convicted bookmaker William Kohne to three years imprisonment and a fine of $10,000, May 4, 1973; 8.
      - Frank Stringi was ordered to jail today for failure to pay a fine after being charged with tax evasion and defrauding the government, May 9, 1973; 9.
      - A federal court convicted Raymond Nolan for attempted extortion, May 9, 1973; 10.
      - Special agents of the ATF arrested H. Milton Every and searched his residence seizing over 300 firearms, May 9, 1973; 11.
      - Over 25 FBI agents carried out coordinated raids on 11 suspected illegal gambling sites in Braddock, PA, May 14, 1973; 12.
      - Flushing out those on the take constitutes a high priority for federal law enforcement efforts, May 15, 1973; 13.
      - A federal court jury convicted William Miller of assaulting two special agents of the FBI with a deadly weapon, May 18, 1973; 14.
      - A third special federal grand jury to investigate organized crime and racketeering in Western PA will be empanelled, May 22, 1973; 15.
      - Judge Edward Dumbauld sentenced Raymond and Roxanne Johnson for violation of federal narcotic laws, May 22, 1973; 16.
      - Federal agents arrested three Pittsburgh men in a major development concerning a 1971 gangland-style bombing, May, 1973; 17.
      - Thornburgh announced that a special federal grand jury returned a 10-count indictment against 17 defendants on conspiracy charges, May 31, 1973; 18.
      - A federal court jury convicted two Pittsburgh men on charges of violating the anti-gambling provisions of the 1970 Organized Crime Control Act, June 4, 1973; 19.
      - Thornburgh charged a local postal employee in connection with a numbers business being conducted in the Federal Courthouse Building, June 4, 1973; 20.
      - ATF agents are searching for three fugitives charged with assaulting two ATF agents while in the performance of their duties, June 6, 1973; 21.
      - FBI agents arrested Anthony Michael Grosso on charges of attempting to fix the jury during his recent federal court trial, June 8, 1973; 22.
      - FBI agents took Louis Raucci into custody on charges of obstructing a federal crime investigation, June 11, 1973; 23.
      - Thornburgh urged PA Crime Commission's public disclosure of its list of PA businesses that are owned or controlled by organized crime, June 11, 1973; 24.
      - William Mellon Hitchcock will plead guilty to federal income tax fraud charges, June 14, 1973; 25.
      - Thornburgh will attend a conference of top federal law enforcement officials in Chicago, June, 1973; 26.
      - A federal grand jury indicted six people on charges of violating the anti-gambling provisions of the Organized Crime Control Act of 1970, June 19, 1973; 27.
      - June 29, 1973 is an important date to young men who are residents of Western PA and have failed to comply with the orders of their local draft boards, June, 1973; 28.
      - Louis Raucci was indicted on charges of obstructing a federal criminal investigation, June 19, 1973; 29.
      - Dr. Harry Lykens was sentenced to pay a fine and serve three years probation for willfully failing to file an income tax return, June 20, 1973; 30.
      - A special federal grand jury to investigate organized crime and racketeering in the Erie area will be empanelled on Tuesday, June, 1973; 31.
      - A federal grand jury indicted a McKeesport man on two counts charging involvement in a loan-sharking scheme, June 21, 1973; 32.
      - Anthony Michael Grosso was jailed on charges of violating the anti-gambling provisions of the 1970 Organized Crime Control Act, June 25, 1973; 33.
      - Over 150 friends of Assistant United States Attorney W. Wendell Stanton will honor him at a testimonial dinner, June, 1973; 34.
      - Thornburgh filed the first case in the nation charging a violation of the Federal Odometer Disclosures Regulations, June 28, 1973; 35.
    - July-September, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Mary Ann Houmis was held for a hearing on charges that she aided and abetted the counterfeiting of bonds, July 3, 1973; 1.
      - Two Michigan men pleaded guilty of attempted extortion against the Gulf Oil Corporation in Pittsburgh, July 10, 1973; 2.
      - Thornburgh charged Valvoline Oil Company with failure to promptly report an oil spill at its refinery in Freedom, PA, July 17, 1973; 3.
      - Thornburgh was the recipient of a special medallion award in recognition of his outstanding contribution to the field of narcotic law enforcement, July 23, 1973; 4.
      - Reform of our police, courts and correctional systems must be systematically undertaken, July 26, 1973; 5.
      - A federal grand jury charged two Pittsburgh men with using the U.S. mail to defraud a metals recycling firm, July 27, 1973; 6.
      - A federal grand jury returned an 8-count indictment charging a Waynesburg, PA high school teacher and two youths with drug trafficking., July 27, 1973; 7.
      - A federal grand jury has indicted three Pittsburgh area persons on federal charges in connection with a fraudulent interstate baby selling scheme, July, 1973; 8.
      - Collections by the U.S. Attorney's office of funds owing the federal government nearly doubled during the fiscal year ending June 30, 1973, July, 1973; 9.
      - President Nixon submitted to the U.S. Senate the reappointment of Thornburgh to serve a second four-year term as U.S. Attorney for Western PA, August 9, 1973; 10.
      - A federal grand jury indicted three Pittsburgh men on charges of resisting, impeding and interfering with a Special Agent of the ATF, August 15, 1973; 11.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Michael Busic, Anthony LaRocca, Jr. and Kenneth Murray on assault and stealing charges, August 15, 1973; 12.
      - Secret Service agents arrested five Pittsburgh area men involved in a massive federal savings bond counterfeiting ring, August 16, 1973; 13.
      - A Penn Hills businessman was sentenced in federal court to 60 days in jail for filing a false income tax return, August 16, 1973; 14.
      - A federal grand jury returned a new indictment against former Chief of Allegheny County District Attorney Robert Duggan's "Racket Squad," charging income tax fraud and acceptance of racket payoffs, August 22, 1973; 15.
      - A federal grand jury returned a four count indictment charging an Erie resident with embezzling union funds and submitting false income tax returns, August 28, 1973; 16.
      - "Racket Squad" Chief Samuel G. Ferraro will be arraigned before U.S. Magistrate Sensenich tomorrow, August 30, 1973; 17.
      - Pennsylvania Industrial Chemical Corporation entered a plea of nolo contendere to criminal charges of polluting the Monongahela River, September 4, 1973; 18.
      - A federal grand jury indicted W.A. Boyle on a charge of conspiring to kill union official Joseph Yablonski, September 6, 1973; 19.
      - Trial of ten defendants charged with involvement in an international heroin smuggling operation is scheduled to begin tomorrow, September 9, 1973; 20.
      - U.S. Attorney General Elliot Richardson has named Thornburgh as one of 15 members of a newly-formed U.S. Attorneys' Advisory Committee to the Attorney General, September, 1973; 21.
      - Thornburgh will attend the first meeting of the U.S. Attorneys' Advisory Committee to the Attorney General in Washington, D.C., September 20, 1973; 22.
      - Thornburgh announced two new appointments as part of a realignment of assignments within the U.S. Attorney's office, September 25, 1973; 23.
      - Three Pittsburgh steel manufacturers entered no contest pleas in federal court to criminal charges of polluting the Monongahela and Ohio rivers, September 27, 1973; 24.
    - October-December, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - A New York man pleaded guilty in mid-trial to extortion and assault charges in federal district court in Pittsburgh, October 1, 1973; 1.
      - Three Western PA pollution "bounty hunters" will receive the first financial return on their efforts, October 1, 1973; 2.
      - Three Western PA residents pleaded guilty to charges of manufacturing and distributing amphetamine sulfate, October 3, 1973; 3.
      - Judge Ralph Scalera sentenced the operator of a Pittsburgh-Law Vegas gambling junket to 30 days in jail, October 10, 1973; 4.
      - Thornburgh will attend a meeting of the U.S. Attorneys' Advisory Committee to the Attorney General in Kansas City, Missouri, October 11, 1973; 5.
      - Judge Herbert Sorg sentenced Richard Bonner to imprisonment for a total of 12 years for two bank robberies, October 12, 1973; 6.
      - Judge Herbert Sorg sentenced Alfred Nannini, Jr. to 3 years imprisonment on charges of possessing and passing counterfeit bills, October 12, 1973; 7.
      - A special federal grand jury returned a two-count indictment charging 11 individuals with conspiracy and the operation of a high stakes illegal gambling operation, October 17, 1973; 8.
      - The Mayor of Bedford, Eldon G. Studebaker, and three other men were indicted on charges of using the mail to defraud insurance companies, October 17, 1973; 9.
      - Thornburgh announced the appointment of David Atkins as an Assistant United States Attorney, October 19, 1973; 10.
      - A federal grand jury returned a 47-count indictment against a Pittsburgh doctor on charges of illegally dispensing narcotics, October 26, 1973; 11.
      - A federal grand jury indicted a U.S. Air Force sergeant from Clairton, PA on charges of heroin importation and distribution, October 26, 1973; 12.
      - Judge Herbert Sorg sentenced Joseph Gera to six months imprisonment and fined him on counts of preparing false income tax returns, November 15, 1973; 13.
      - Special Agents of the Secret Service arrested the last of four suspects charged with printing over $3 million in counterfeit stamps, November 15, 1973; 14.
      - A federal grand jury returned three indictments charging 22 Erie area individuals with violations of the federal gambling laws, November 19, 1973; 15.
      - Three top level executives in the illegal numbers gambling operation run by Anthony Grosso were found guilty of violating federal anti-gambling laws, November 26, 1973; 16.
      - A Mercer County physician pleaded not guilty in federal court to charges of illegal distribution of drugs and a failing to maintain proper prescription records, November 29, 1973; 17.
      - Fifteen more members of the $30 million per year illegal numbers gambling organization headed by Anthony Grosso were indicted today, November 30, 1973; 18.
      - Thornburgh will be among the environmental experts participating in the presentation of a "Practical Course in Environmental Law.", December 4, 1973; 19.
      - The U.S. Court of Appeals upheld the jailing of Samuel Ferraro of Pittsburgh on contempt of court charges, December 5, 1973; 20.
      - Thomas Pecora, Business Manager of Laborers Local 1058, was convicted this week, December 7, 1973; 21.
      - Federal authorities took action to compel disclosure of certain books and records relating to Euthenics Systems Corp., December 7, 1973; 22.
      - Attorney General Robert Bork will present a Special Commendation Award to Miss Stella Kourakos\, Administrative Assistant to U.S. Attorney Thornburgh, December 9, 1973; 23.
      - Thornburgh announced the appointment of Craig R. McKay as an Assistant U.S. Attorney, December 10, 1973; 24.
      - A federal grand jury returned an indictment charging two men with the conduct of three fraudulent charity schemes, December 13, 1973; 25.
      - A woman, involved in the $30 million per year illegal numbers gambling operation run by Anthony Grosso, was ordered to jail today, December 20, 1973; 26.
    - January-March, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - An Erie labor leader entered a plea of guilty to two counts of an indictment charging embezzling of union funds and submitting a false income tax return, January 2, 1974; 1.
      - Thornburgh will be working both sides of the street in appearances before local political groups this month in Pittsburgh, January, 1974; 2.
      - A federal grand jury returned a three-count indictment charging an Erie fugitive with the kidnapping-murder of Donald Stafford, January 18, 1974; 3.
      - Valvoline Oil Company was found guilty in federal district court of failing to report a discharge of oil from its facility at Freedom, PA, January 21, 1974; 4.
      - Five more defendants in the Anthony Grosso $30 million a year in illegal numbers gambling operation entered guilty pleas today, January 28, 1974; 5.
      - A federal grand jury indicted the former president of Bidwell Enterprises, Inc. and his brother on mail fraud charges, February 6, 1974; 6.
      - The mastermind of a massive home repair swindle in the Pittsburgh area was sentenced to ten years imprisonment, February 7, 1974; 7.
      - An Erie labor leader was sentenced to four years imprisonment by federal Judge William Knox, February 7, 1974; 8.
      - A Mercer County physician was ordered to jail for illegal drug distribution and failure to maintain proper prescription records, February 8, 1974; 9.
      - Jack Nard was sentenced to 36 months imprisonment and to pay a fine of $10\,000 on pleas of guilty and "no defense" to a three-count indictment charging him with income tax fraud, February 11, 1974; 10.
      - Samuel Ferraro was released from federal custody after he agreed to testify before the federal grand jury investigating organized crime and official corruption in Allegheny County, February 12, 1974; 11.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Paul M. Hilbert\, former Director of District 15, United Steelworkers of America (AFL-CIO) for embezzling $7,500 from the union, February 20, 1974; 12.
      - Thornburgh will be at the U.S. Department of Justice in Washington, D.C. to attend a meeting of the U.S. Attorneys' Advisory Committee to the Attorney General, February 23, 1974; 13.
      - Thornburgh will address participants in the "Program for Executives" of Carnegie Mellon University's Graduate School of Industrial Administration on "Challenges to Criminal Justice.", March 5, 1974; 14.
      - Allegheny County District Attorney Robert W. Duggan was indicted by a federal grand jury on eight counts of tax fraud, March 5, 1974; 15.
      - A federal grand jury returned indictments charging residents with failing to register with the Selective Service System within the time prescribed by law, March 7, 1974; 17.
      - A federal court jury returned a guilty verdict against a Pittsburgh physician on charges of illegally dispensing controlled drugs, March 8, 1974; 18.
      - Thornburgh will depart for a two-day visit to Iowa City, Iowa where he will present a series of lectures on law enforcement and the criminal justice system at the University of Iowa, March 28, 1974; 19.
    - April-June, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Federal Drug Enforcement Administration Agents from Pittsburgh arrested nine persons on federal narcotics charges, April 10, 1974; 1.
      - A federal grand jury indicted four persons in its continuing investigation of official corruption in the Greater Pittsburgh area, April 10, 1974; 2.
      - A federal grand jury indicted a Pittsburgh attorney and four area residents on charges of conspiring to stage a fake automobile accident, April 11, 1974; 3.
      - A federal grand jury indicted an Erie resident in connection with the embezzlement of over $2,900 from the Union Bank and Trust Company of Erie, April 11, 1974; 4.
      - A federal grand jury indicted a Venango County businessman and his former bookkeeper on federal income tax charges, April 11, 1974; 5.
      - A federal grand jury indicted Samuel Canterman on two counts of filing fraudulent income tax returns, April 11, 1974; 6.
      - A Venango County man was indicted in Pittsburgh on charges of illegal wiretapping, April 11, 1974; 7.
      - A former proprietor of a typewriter sales agency was sentenced to serve 20 days in jail for tax fraud, April 16, 1974; 8.
      - A convicted heroin dealer was sentenced to jail on federal income tax charges by federal Judge Daniel Snyder, April 17, 1974; 9.
      - Thornburgh confirmed that a subpoena has been issued to compel the testimony of Michael Genovese, April 19, 1974; 10.
      - A special federal grand jury returned an indictment against 14 individuals alleged to be involved in the distribution of heroin and cocaine in Mercer County, April 19, 1974; 11.